# **Gatlin Cooper**

# **Web Application Development**

gicooper99@gmail.com | (541) 279-8155 | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

## **Summary**

Software Engineer with experience in several varied professional and academic development projects. Working with an array of web application languages and tools, including TypeScript, React, Python, SQL, RESTful API architecture, Ruby on Rails, Docker, and a variety of AWS cloud services.

#### **Education**

# **Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science**

Oregon State University, Cascades 2023 – 3.72 Magna Cum Laude Honors

# **Employment**

#### **CBT Nuggets/Adept Software Engineer**

Remote

Winter 2023 - Present

- Became acquainted with a range of cloud services and technologies, including Docker, Lambda, ECS, Fargate, and ECR
- Leveraged custom APIs, AWS, and Dockerized containers to streamline internal workflows through automated CRON jobs and Slackbot integrations
- Translated Webflow prototype designs into responsive front-end interfaces

# **CBT Nuggets/Software Engineering Intern**

Remote

Summer 2022 - Winter 2023

- Spearheaded comprehensive front-end design revamps, translating prototype designs into polished, user-friendly interfaces that enhance both trainer and learner experiences
- Championed website accessibility initiatives by implementing custom responsive keyboard navigation, ensuring a seamless experience for users of all abilities
- Developed and published an NPM package to streamline testing processes, increasing code quality and development efficiency whilst ensuring strong website accessibility

# **Projects**

#### **Forging Brains**

Spring 2023 – Present

- Independently gathered initial expectations, criteria, and functionality made by client to develop a fully functional Podcast website themed around Blacksmithing
- Continue receiving and implementing feedback and content update requirements for the project

## **BDA-Explorer**

Fall 2021 - Summer 2022

- Collaborating with partner developer to implement numerous functional and aesthetic changes/updates to a live Ruby on Rails application on Heroku, with integration on AWS
- Developed distinct in-depth full-stack features including PostgreSQL database expansion